Guide to the Theodore Rockwell Papers 1915-2013
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center
- U.S Navy, 1949-2012; Series IV
  Series IV is comprised of materials relating to Rockwell's involvement in the development of the U.S. Navy's nuclear-powered fleet from 1949-1964. The series includes design documents; correspondence, including letters from Admiral Rickover; technical reports authored by Rockwell; Navy Nuclear Propulsion Program Reports; materials from the U.S. Navy Bureau of Ships (BuShips); and nuclear reactor case histories. The series also includes materials generated and collected by William Wegner and John W. Crawford, Jr., both members of Admiral Rickover's administrative team comprising professional correspondence, reports, speeches, and reference materials dating from their Navy careers, biographical sketches, and personal correspondence with Rockwell. Also included are subject files relating to the Sasebo, Japan contamination incident and the capture of German submarine U-234.
  The series also contains extensive Navy memorabilia including invitations and programs from numerous Navy events such as keel layings, launchings, and decommissionings; promotional booklets and pamphlets; ship and shipyard newsletters; photographs; presskits; and documents provided to non-crewmen aboard ships. The collection also includes commemorative envelopes, or cachets, honoring Navy events and historical moments in ocean exploration and flight. Many envelopes were sent to Rockwell courtesy of Admiral Rickover and include letters from Rickover and other Navy personnel, photographs, and memorabilia. Vessels represented in the collection include the USS Enterprise, Nautilus, Sea Wolf, Skipjack, and Triton, among others.
  The series also represents Rockwell's interest in the achievements of Admiral Hyman G. Rickover which culminated in The Rickover Effect, a 1992 biography of the Admiral published by the U.S. Naval Institute Press. The series includes correspondence, drafts, reviews, and promotion and publishing files relating to The Rickover Effect, an extensive collection of reports, newspaper clippings, publications, speeches, and correspondence reflecting the life and work of Admiral Rickover, documents from the PBS documentary Rickover: The Birth of Nuclear Power, and materials from an incomplete project concept to produce a motion picture film on the life of Rickover.
  - Articles and Newsclippings, 1954-2010 (Box-folder 14.4)
  - Barnes, Willis C., 1986-1993 (Box-folder 14.5)
  - Commemorative Envelopes: Air, Sea, and Space Events, 1960-2000 (Box-folder 14.6)
  - Commemorative Envelopes: SSN-571 - SSN-709, 1958-2004 (Box-folder 14.7)
  - Commemorative Envelopes: SSBN-598 - SSBN-658, 1959-1965 (Box-folder 14.8)
  - Commemorative Envelopes: ARS-40, CGN-9, CVAN-65, DLGN-25, DLGN-35, NR-1, SSGN-587, 1959-1969 (Box-folder 14.9)
  - Congressional Hearings, 1956-1995 (Box-folder 15.1)
  - Correspondence, 1952-1962 (Box-folder 15.2)
  - Correspondence, 1995-2010 (Box-folder 15.3)
  - Crawford, John W.., 1954-1996 (Box-folder 15.4)
  - Design Documents, 1954-1960 (Box-folder 15.5)
  - Heppenheimer, Tom, Countdown: A History of Space Flight Draft, 1997 (Box-folder 15.6)
  - Memorabilia: U.S. Navy, circa 1953-2012 (Box-folder 15.7)
  - Memorabilia: U.S. Navy (oversized), 1954-1962 (Box 84)
  - Memorabilia: USS Enterprise (CVAN-65), 1960-2010 (Box-folder 15.8)
  - Memorabilia: USS Nautilus (SSN-571), 1952-2005 (Box-folder 16.1)
  - Memorabilia: USS Nautilus (SSN-571) Needlepoint Design, circa 1990 (Box 84)
  - Memorabilia: USS Sea Wolf (SSN-575), 1953-1957 (Box-folder 16.2)
  - Memorabilia: USS Skipjack (SSN-585), 1958-1959 (Box-folder 16.3)
  - Memorabilia: USS Triton (SSRN-586), 1958-1960 (Box-folder 16.4)
  - Memorabilia: CGN-9, DLFN-25, and SSGN-587, 1957-1962 (Box-folder 16.5)
  - Memorabilia: SSBN-598 - SSBN-664, 1959-1964 (Box-folder 16.6)
  - Memorabilia: SSN-578 - SSN-709, 1956-1995 (Box-folder 16.7)
  - Naval Reactors Group Reunion, 1992 (Box-folder 16.8)
  - Naval Reactors Group Reunion Photographs, 1992 (Box-folder 17.1)
  - Naval Reactors Group Reunion Photographs, 1992 (Box-folder 17.2)
  - Naval Reactors Group 50th Anniversary Celebration, 1997-2001 (Box-folder 17.3)
  - Newsclippings (oversized), 1952-1974 (Box 84)
  - Oliver Jr., David R., "Managing a Culture of Success", 2012 (Box-folder 17.4)
  - Photographs, circa 1955-1970 (Box-folder 17.5)
  - Promotional Materials, circa 1954-2000 (Box-folder 17.6)
  - Hyman G. Rickover, 1952-2003 (Box-folder 18.1)
  - Hyman G. Rickover, 1955-2004 (Box-folder 18.2)
  - Hyman G. Rickover, 1956-2008 (Box-folder 18.3)
  - Hyman G. Rickover, 1958-1990 (Box-folder 18.4)
  - Hyman G. Rickover, circa 1960-2000 (Box-folder 18.5)
  - Hyman G. Rickover, 1982-2011 (Box-folder 18.6)
  - Hyman G. Rickover (oversized), 1959-1982 (Box 84)
  - Hyman G. Rickover Articles, 1957-1981 (Box-folder 19.1)
  - Hyman G. Rickover Awards and Memorial, 1959-1986 (Box-folder 19.2)
  - Hyman G. Rickover Correspondence, 1949-1972 (Box-folder 19.3)
  - The Admiral H. G. Rickover Foundation, 1984-1992 (Box-folder 19.4)
  - Hyman G. Rickover motion picture film, 1997-2004 (Box-folder 19.5)
  - Hyman G. Rickover Speeches, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 19.6)
  - Hyman G. Rickover Speeches, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 20.1)
  - Hyman G. Rickover Speeches, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 20.2)
  - Hyman G. Rickover Speeches, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 20.3)
  - Hyman G. Rickover Television Documentary: Rickover: The Birth of Nuclear Power, 2010-2012 (Box-folder 20.4)
  - Rockwell Patent: "Thermal Neutron Shield and Method for Making Same," 2,727,996, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 20.5)
  - Rockwell Publication Drafts, circa 1954-1990 (Box-folder 20.6)
  - Rockwell Publication: "Naval Reactors Program: A Joint Navy-Atomic Energy Commission Program", 1963 (Box-folder 20.7)
  - Rockwell Publication: "Pressurized Water Reactor (PWR) Water Chemistry", 1955 (Box-folder 20.8)
  - Rockwell Publication: The Rickover Effect Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 20.9)
  - Rockwell Publication: The Rickover Effect Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 21.1)
  - Rockwell Publication: The Rickover Effect Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 21.2)
  - Rockwell Publication: The Rickover Effect Correspondence, 1993-2009 (Box-folder 21.3)
  - Rockwell Publication: The Rickover Effect Draft, circa 1991 (Box-folder 21.4)
  - Rockwell Publication: The Rickover Effect Excerpts, circa 1992 (Box-folder 21.5)
  - Rockwell Publication: The Rickover Effect Figures and Photographs, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 21.6)
  - Rockwell Publication: The Rickover Effect Permissions Agreements, 1993-2005 (Box-folder 21.7)
  - Rockwell Publication: The Rickover Effect Promotional Materials, 1992-2012 (Box-folder 22.1)
  - Rockwell Publication: The Rickover Effect Publication and Sales, 1991-2010 (Box-folder 22.2)
  - Rockwell Publication: The Rickover Effect Reviews, 1992-2000 (Box-folder 22.3)
  - Rockwell Publication: The Rickover Effect Review Letters, 1991 (Box-folder 22.4)
  - Rockwell Publication: The Rickover Effect Review Letters, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 22.5)
  - Rockwell Publication: The Rickover Effect, 1992-1999 (Box-folder 23.1)
  - Rockwell Publication: "Some Problems in the Application of Nuclear Propulsion to Naval Vessels, circa 1958 (Box-folder 23.2)
  - Rockwell Speeches, 1960-1994 (Box-folder 23.3)
  - Rockwell Speech Notes, circa 1993-1994 (Box-folder 23.4)
  - Sasebo, Japan Contamination Incident, 1968 (Box-folder 23.5)
  - Shippingport Atomic Power Station, 1954 (Box-folder 23.6)
  - Submarine Force Library and Museum Association, 1984-2010 (Box-folder 23.7)
  - Submarine Force Library and Museum Association, The Klaxon, 1994-2010 (Box-folder 23.8)
  - U-234 Capture, 1945-1993 (Box-folder 23.9)
  - U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, 1955-1960 (Box-folder 23.10)
  - U.S. General Accounting Office, "Nuclear Submarines: Navy Efforts to Reduce Inactivation Costs", 1992 (Box-folder 23.11)
  - U.S. Naval Nuclear Propulsion Program Reports, 1987-1997 (Box-folder 23.12)
  - U.S. Naval Nuclear Propulsion Program Reports, 2011 (Box-folder 23.13)
  - U.S. Naval Nuclear Propulsion Programs Reports, 2012 (Box-folder 24.1)
  - U.S. Navy Bureau of Ships, 1944-1960 (Box-folder 24.2)
  - U.S. Navy Nuclear Reactors Case Histories, circa 1955 (Box-folder 24.3)
  - USS Nautilus Alumni Association, 1985-2006 (Box-folder 24.4)
  - William Wegner, 1959-2010 (Box-folder 24.5)
- MPR Associates, Inc., 1963-2013; Series V
  Series V is comprised of documents relating to the operation of MPR Associates, Inc., a nuclear engineering firm founded in 1964 by Naval Reactors alumni Harry Mandil, Robert Panoff, and Theodore Rockwell. The series includes information on a proposed partnership between MPR and Toshiba to develop and evaluate Dr. Sadao Hattori's 4S Reactor; a file on MPR employee Norman Cole, Jr.; company correspondence and meeting minutes; a proposed partnership between MPR and the Lewis-Sigler Genomics Institute; a series of documents collected by Rockwell reflecting MPR's company philosophy; and MPR promotional materials including event invitations, an informational pamphlet, several issues of company publication MPR Profile, and essays on professional engineering by Panoff and Rockwell. The series also includes files on nuclear medicine, reactor safety, Ranque-Hilsch vortex tubes, a diagram of an MPR design for a nuclear-powered merchant ship, and transparencies from a speech titled "On Being a Professional" given by Rockwell at an MPR informational meeting.
  - 4S (Super Safe, Small and Simple) Reactor, 2001 (Box-folder 24.6)
  - Cole Jr., Norman M., 1993-1998 (Box-folder 24.7)
  - Correspondence and Meeting Minutes, 1969-2012 (Box-folder 24.8)
  - Lewis-Sigler Institute for Integrative Genomics, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 24.9)
  - MPR Philosophy, 1963-2013 (Box-folder 25.1)
  - MPR Promotional Materials, 1967-2009 (Box-folder 25.2)
  - Nuclear Medicine, 2000 (Box-folder 25.3)
  - Nuclear Merchant Ship Design, circa 1980 (Box-folder 25.4)
  - Ranque-Hilsch Vortex Tube, 1934-1971 (Box-folder 25.5)
  - Reactor Safety, 1967-1987 (Box-folder 25.6)
  - Rockwell Speech: "On Being a Professional", 2002 (Box-folder 25.7)
- Radiation, Science, and Health, Inc., 1981-2009; Series VI
  Series VI is comprised of documents from Radiation, Science, and Health, Inc., a not-for-profit nuclear power advocacy organization founded by James Muckerheide (president) and Ted Rockwell (vice president) in 1996. RHS was founded as a tool for independent radiation experts to influence radiation policy, especially relating to restrictions governing low level radiation. The series includes internal correspondence and documents; promotional correspondence to RSH members and supporters; lobbying correspondence to legislators and other government officials; subject files on radiation exposure; reports from the National Research Council (NRC) and the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA); and documents regarding partnerships with the Washington Legal Foundation and Eagle Alliance.
  Of particular interest are materials documenting RSH's 2000-2003 challenge to the Environmental Protection Agency's rules on radionuclides in drinking water. This includes several editions of RSH's report "Low Level Radiation Health Effects: Compiling the Data," an official response to the EPA's drinking water policy, and documentation from a lawsuit filed against the EPA by the city of Waukesha, Wisconsin, the Nuclear Energy Institute, Inc., the National Mining Association, and RHS, Inc.
  - Administrative Documents, 1996-2002 (Box-folder 25.8)
  - Comby, Bruno, "Environmentalists for Nuclear Energy", 1996 (Box-folder 25.9)
  - Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 25.10)
  - Correspondence, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 26.1)
  - Correspondence, 1997-2002 (Box-folder 26.2)
  - National Research Council, "Biological Effects of Ionizing Radiation (BEIR VII), 2006-2009 (Box-folder 26.3)
  - Promotional Correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 26.4)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1956-2000 (Box-folder 26.5)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1981-2000 (Box-folder 27.1)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1997-2001 (Box-folder 27.2)
  - RSH Organizational Records, 1996-2007 (Box-folder 27.3)
  - RSH Publication Drafts, 1996-2001 (Box-folder 27.4)
  - RSH Published Statements, 1997-2008 (Box-folder 27.5)
  - RSH Report: Low Level Radiation Health Effects: Compiling the Data," Revision 1, 1998 (Box-folder 27.6)
  - RSH Report: Low Level Radiation Health Effects: Compiling the Data," Revision 2, 1999 (Box-folder 28.1)
  - RSH Report: Low Level Radiation Health Effects: Compiling the Data," Revision 3, 2000 (Box-folder 28.2)
  - RSH Report: Low Level Radiation Health Effects: Compiling the Data," Revision 4, 2001 (Box-folder 28.3)
  - RSH/Eagle Alliance Cooperation, 1998-2002 (Box-folder 28.4)
  - U.S. Environmental Protection Agency Radionuclides in Drinking Water Rule, RSH Response, 2000 (Box-folder 28.5)
  - U.S. Environmental Protection Agency: "Radionuclides Notice of Data Availability Technical Support Document", 2000 (Box-folder 28.6)
  - Washington Legal Foundation Proposal, 2000 (Box-folder 28.7)
  - Waukesha, Wisconsin et al v. U.S. Environmental Protection Agency Joint Reply Brief Petitioners, 2002 (Box-folder 28.8)
  - Waukesha, Wisconsin Water Contamination, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 28.9)
- Nuclear Power, 1915-2013; Series VII
  Series VII is comprised of research materials generated, collected, and assembled by Rockwell relating to nuclear energy and is reflective of his pro-nuclear position. The series includes correspondence; clippings, photocopies, and web articles from popular media sources such as Newsweek, Time, and Science; informational and promotional materials from pro- and anti-nuclear interest groups; technical reports; newsletters; and an extensive body of material written for speaking events and publications by Rockwell.
  Much of the collection addresses the role of nuclear power as an energy source in the late 20th and early 21st centuries and the health and environmental effects of exposure to low level radiation. Other topics include regulation and regulatory reform in the nuclear power industry; nuclear disasters including Chernobyl, Three Mile Island, and Fukushima Daiichi; the utility of non-nuclear fuel sources; public opinion, fear, and misinformation regarding radiation safety; nuclear waste management; nuclear terrorism; and nuclear legislation. The series includes materials from a variety of special interest groups such as the Atomic Industrial Forum, Americans for Nuclear Energy, the American Nuclear Society, Eagle Alliance, and Greenpeace. Also included are publications and correspondence from professionals in the nuclear power industry including T.D. Luckey, Jim Muckerheide, Jerry Cuttler, Myron Pollycove, John Cameron, Jovan Jovanovich, and Sadao Hattori. Materials in the collection also address the effects of radiation therapy and include publications and firsthand accounts documenting the treatment of Edward J. Bauser, a Navy colleague of Rockwell. Documents containing unpublished information regarding Bauser's health and medical treatment are restricted.
  The series also includes drafts and published copies of articles, books, and speeches written by Rockwell in support of increased reliance on nuclear energy on a global scale. Included are materials from his book Power to the People, notes from his participation in a 2009 GOP Senate hearing, and copies of numerous articles published in industry and popular publications.
  - Alternative Energy Sources, 1986-2009 (Box-folder 28.10)
  - Alternative Energy Sources: Biofuel, 2009 (Box-folder 28.11)
  - Alternative Energy Sources: Coal, 1979-2009 (Box-folder 29.1)
  - Alternative Energy Sources: Solar, 1979-2009 (Box-folder 29.2)
  - Alternative Energy Sources: Wind, 1984-2010 (Box-folder 29.3)
  - American Nuclear Society, 1986-2013 (Box-folder 29.4)
  - American Nuclear Society, Nuclear News, 2004-2007 (Box-folder 29.5)
  - American Nuclear Society, Radiation Protection and Shielding Division, 2001-2011 (Box-folder 29.6)
  - Americans for Nuclear Energy, Inc., The Nuclear Advocate, 1983-1995 (Box-folder 29.7)
  - Anti-Nuclear Campaign, 1977-1997 (Box-folder 29.8)
  - Anti-Nuclear Campaign, 1978-1986 (Box-folder 30.1)
  - Anti-Nuclear Campaign, 1979-1997 (Box-folder 30.2)
  - Anti-Nuclear Campaign, 1979-1998 (Box-folder 30.3)
  - Anti-Nuclear Campaign, 1980-1997 (Box-folder 30.4)
  - Anti-Nuclear Campaign, 1990-2000 (Box-folder 30.5)
  - Background Radiation, 1976-2001 (Box-folder 31.1)
  - Background Radiation, 1991-2002 (Box-folder 31.2)
  - Chernobyl Disaster, 1986-2011 (Box-folder 31.3)
  - Chernobyl Disaster, 1987-2010 (Box-folder 31.4)
  - Doctors for Disaster Preparedness, Newsletter, 2007-2010 (Box-folder 31.5)
  - Eagle Alliance, 1995-2003 (Box-folder 31.6)
  - Electric Vehicles, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 32.1)
  - Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program, 1996-2001 (Box-folder 32.2)
  - Environmentalism, 1970-1996 (Box-folder 32.3)
  - Environmental Health, 1979-2005 (Box-folder 32.4)
  - Foulke, Larry, 2004-2012 (Box-folder 32.5)
  - Fukushima Daiichi Disaster, 2011-2012 (Box-folder 32.6)
  - Global Energy Needs, 1940-2010 (Box-folder 32.7)
  - Global Energy Needs, 1979-2000 (Box-folder 32.8)
  - Global Energy Needs, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 33.1)
  - Global Warming, 1990-2009 (Box-folder 33.2)
  - Green, Wayne, Cold Fusion, 1994 (Box-folder 33.3)
  - Green, Wayne, Cold Fusion, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 33.4)
  - Hanford Site, 1996 (Box-folder 33.5)
  - Hanford Site, 1997 (Box-folder 33.6)
  - Hayden, Howard, The Energy Advocate, 2000-2005 (Box-folder 33.7)
  - Hayden, Howard, The Energy Advocate, 2005-2012 (Box-folder 34.1)
  - Health Physics Society, 1995-2011 (Box-folder 34.2)
  - Ladd, Anthony E., "A Social Movement Analysis of the of the American Antinuclear Movement", 1981 (Box-folder 34.3)
  - Liburdy, Robert P., Scientific Misconduct, 1995-1999 (Box-folder 34.4)
  - Morrell, Prior, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 34.5)
  - National Capital Union Presbytery Task Force on Energy, 1975-1981 (Box-folder 34.6)
  - National Capital Union Presbytery Task Force on Energy, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 34.7)
  - National Council for Environmental Balance, 1978-1985 (Box-folder 35.1)
  - National Council on Radiation Protection, 1995-2004 (Box-folder 35.2)
  - Natural Resources Scarcity, 1977-1995 (Box-folder 35.3)
  - New York Academy of Science, circa 1990-2012 (Box-folder 35.4)
  - Northeast Regional Environmental Public Health Center, BELLE Newsletter, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 35.5)
  - Northeast Regional Environmental Public Health Center, BELLE Newsletter, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 35.6)
  - Northeast Regional Environmental Public Health Center, BELLE Newsletter, 2000-2004 (Box-folder 36.1)
  - Nuclear Energy Institute, 1994-2002 (Box-folder 36.2)
  - Nuclear Industry Promotional Materials, 1950-2010 (Box-folder 36.3)
  - Nuclear Power, 1960-1993 (Box-folder 36.4)
  - Nuclear Power, 1967-1995 (Box-folder 36.5)
  - Nuclear Power, 1974-1994 (Box-folder 37.1)
  - Nuclear Power, 1977-1997 (Box-folder 37.2)
  - Nuclear Power, 1977-2000 (Box-folder 37.3)
  - Nuclear Power, 1978-2006 (Box-folder 37.4)
  - Nuclear Power, 1979-1986 (Box-folder 37.5)
  - Nuclear Power, 1979-1997 (Box-folder 38.1)
  - Nuclear Power, 1980-1997 (Box-folder 38.2)
  - Nuclear Power, 1981-1997 (Box-folder 38.3)
  - Nuclear Power, 1986-2002 (Box-folder 38.4)
  - Nuclear Power, 1988-2003 (Box-folder 38.5)
  - Nuclear Power, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 39.1)
  - Nuclear Power, 1996-2010 (Box-folder 39.2)
  - Nuclear Power, 1996-2011 (Box-folder 39.3)
  - Nuclear Power, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 39.4)
  - Nuclear Power, 1997-2011 (Box-folder 39.5)
  - Nuclear Power, 2007-2010 (Box-folder 40.1)
  - Nuclear Power (German-language texts), 1986-1998 (Box-folder 40.2)
  - Nuclear Power, Environmental Impact, 1979-2004 (Box-folder 40.3)
  - Nuclear Power, Ethics, 1975-2000 (Box-folder 40.4)
  - Nuclear Power, Ethics, 1976-2000 (Box-folder 40.5)
  - Nuclear Power, Ethics, 1991-2005 (Box-folder 40.6)
  - Nuclear Reactor Design, 1951-2011 (Box-folder 41.1)
  - Nuclear Reactor Design, 1955-2010 (Box-folder 41.2)
  - Nuclear Reactor Regulation, 1972-2011 (Box-folder 41.3)
  - Nuclear Reactor Regulation, 1979-2004 (Box-folder 41.4)
  - Nuclear Science Education, circa 1990-1998 (Box-folder 42.1)
  - Nuclear Science Education, circa 2000 (Box-folder 42.2)
  - Nuclear Weapons, Historic, 1945-2002 (Box-folder 42.3)
  - Nuclear Weapons, Historic, 1945-2010 (Box-folder 42.4)
  - Nuclear Weapons, Modern, 1977-1997 (Box-folder 42.5)
  - Paducah, Kentucky, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 43.1)
  - Physicians for Civil Defense, Civil Defense Perspectives, 2007-2010 (Box-folder 43.2)
  - President's Council of Advisors on Science and Technology, 1997 (Box-folder 43.3)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1915-2007 (Box-folder 43.4)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1957-1999 (Box-folder 43.5)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1966-2000 (Box-folder 43.6)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1967-2000 (Box-folder 44.1)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 44.2)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1973-2000 (Box-folder 44.3)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1973-2011 (Box-folder 44.4)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1977-1982 (Box-folder 44.5)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1977-1997 (Box-folder 45.1)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1977-1997 (Box-folder 45.2)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1979-2009 (Box-folder 45.3)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1980-1999 (Box-folder 45.4)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1980-1999 (Box-folder 45.5)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1980-2000 (Box-folder 46.1)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1980-2000 (Box-folder 46.2)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1980-2002 (Box-folder 46.3)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1980-2006 (Box-folder 46.4)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1980-2010 (Box-folder 46.5)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1980-2010 (Box-folder 47.1)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1981-2000 (Box-folder 47.2)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1981-2000 (Box-folder 47.3)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1981-2010 (Box-folder 47.4)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1982-2000 (Box-folder 47.5)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1982-2005 (Box-folder 48.1)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1985-2000 (Box-folder 48.2)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1991-1999 (Box-folder 48.3)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1991-2009 (Box-folder 48.4)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1992-1999 (Box-folder 48.5)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1994-2000 (Box-folder 49.1)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1996-2002 (Box-folder 49.2)
  - Radiation Exposure, 1999-2011 (Box-folder 49.3)
  - Radiation Protection, 1979-2000 (Box-folder 49.4)
  - Radiation Therapy, 1958-2004 (Box-folder 49.5)
  - Radiation Therapy, 1979-2003 (Box-folder 49.6)
  - Radiation Therapy, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 50.1)
    Additional documents addressing the medical care of Edward J. Bauser from 1999-2002 are restricted and housed separately in box 85.
  - Radioactive Waste Management, 1974-2004 (Box-folder 50.2)
  - Radioactive Waste Management, 1980-2008 (Box-folder 50.3)
  - Radioactive Waste Management, 1990-2004 (Box-folder 50.4)
  - Radioactive Waste Management, 1995-2010 (Box-folder 50.5)
  - Radioactive Waste Management: Plutonium, 1980-1998 (Box-folder 51.1)
  - Radioactive Waste Management: Plutonium, 1991-2000 (Box-folder 51.2)
  - Radioactive Waste Management: Ward Valley, 1995-1999 (Box-folder 51.3)
  - Radioactive Waste Management: Ward Valley, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 51.4)
  - Radon, 1958-2000 (Box-folder 51.5)
  - Radon, 1979-1999 (Box-folder 51.6)
  - Radon, 1981-2000 (Box-folder 52.1)
  - Radon, 1994-2003 (Box-folder 52.2)
  - The Realism Project, 2004 (Box-folder 52.3)
  - Rhodes, Richard, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 52.4)
  - Risk Assessment, 1969-2000 (Box-folder 52.5)
  - Risk Assessment, 1979-1997 (Box-folder 52.6)
  - Risk Assessment, 1979-1999 (Box-folder 53.1)
  - Risk Assessment, 1980-1999 (Box-folder 53.2)
  - Risk Assessment, 1980-2010 (Box-folder 53.3)